Guide to the Furey family papers 1977.331
Brooklyn Historical Society
Furey family papers
1864-1938
Brooklyn Historical Society
Furey, John V.
Furey family
1977.331
0.25 Linear Feet in one box.
Correspondence, deeds, titles, military papers and news clippings pertaining to members of the Furey family including John V. Furey, Robert Furey, Georgianna Furey, and George Furey as well as their family home at 10 8th Avenue in Park Slope.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of acquisition unknown.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series by topic. Series 1: Furey family is arranged alphabetically by first name with the exception of the clippings file which follows the individual family members' papers. Series 2: 10 8th Avenue is arranged chronologically.
Biographical note
Robert Furey Sr. was born June 8, 1803 and died October 11, 1880. He lived on Prospect Place in Brooklyn. His wife Mary Furey was born August 15, 1806 and died March 2, 1883. They had four sons (Robert, William, James, and John) and no daughters.
Robert Furey (Jr.) was born April 5, 1832 and died March 12, 1913 at the Montauk Club in Brooklyn, which was his place of residence at that time. He was a politician and served as an Alderman and Streets Commissioner in Brooklyn. He never married. Upon his death, he left the entirety of his estate to his friend John M. Gray, which resulted in a legal conflict between Gray and Robert's brother John.
John V. Furey was born on May 22, 1839. He had a long career in the United States military. He and his wife Georgianna Furey, along with their daughter George (Georgia) Crook Furey, settled in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn after John's retirement from the military in 1903. John died in 1914 and Georgianna died in 1938. Georgianna's later years were marked by financial struggle and a fight to receive a pension.
Related Materials
Brooklyn, N.Y., Department of Law, Corporation Counsel records (2013.015): Folders Furey, R. (Streets Commissioner), 1867; Furey, Robert - Street cleaning contract dispute, 1894-1895; Johnston, Charles against Robert Furey, et al - Street cleaning contract dispute, 1893.
Letters of James W. Vanderhoef (BCMS.0021)
John Vliet Civil War correspondence (1974.109a)
Bennett family collection of Civil War correspondence and other material (2009.012)
Scope and Contents
The Furey family papers contain correspondence, deeds, titles, and news clippings pertaining to members of the Furey family including John V. Furey, Robert Furey, Georgianna Furey, and George Furey. The property records in the collection pertain to the family home at 10 8th Avenue in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. Also included in the collection are the military papers of John V. Furey.
Families -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real property -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Inheritance and succession; Soldiers -- Pensions; Veterans -- New York (State) -- Kings County
- Series 1: Furey family
  - George (Georgia) Crook Furey, 1913, 1916, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Two documents relating to real estate and insurance (1913 and 1916); a 1938 postcard from the Nebraska Department of Health confirming Furey's birth on October 1, 1880; and a letter from the National Cyclopedia of American Biography regarding the publication of a biography of John V. Furey (1938).
  - Georgianna G. Furey pension documents, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series 1.1: John V. Furey
    - Military papers, 1864-1908 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
      Correspondence and official documents from Furey's military career. Also includes some personal correspondence.
    - Bank account book, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Three letters to Furey from his attorney, Robert H. Ewell.
    - Estate, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robert Furey estate statements and documents, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1893-1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series 2: 10 8th Avenue
  - Deeds, 1891, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Inventory, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bill of sale, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Land title, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)